Edward Twitchell Hall papers 1930-1979
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Career, 1931-1978
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Cynthia Peters Evans, Dissertation: A Proxemic Analysis of Greeting. 1978 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Cynthia Peters Evans, Dissertation: A Proxemic Analysis of Greeting. 1978 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Cynthia Peters Evans, Dissertation: A Proxemic Analysis of Greeting. 1978 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - S. Giedion, The Eternal Present: A Contribution on Constancy and Change, Oxford University Press, London. Galleys with Marginal Notes by Marshall McLuhan. 1964 (Box 39, 1-6)
- Series III: Writings, 1935-1979
  - Papers and Articles: "Report on Archeological Survey of Main Tsegi." 1935 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Articles: "A Method for Obtaining a Plain Surface on Charcoal." 1939 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Articles: "Some Advantages to Be Derived by Including a Dendrochronologist as Staff Member of Field Expeditions in the Southwest." 1939 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Articles: "Recent Clues to Athabascan Prehistory in the Southwest." 1944 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Papers and Articles: "A Commentary on American Higher Education by Professor 'X'." after 1945 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Papers and Articles: "Preserving and Surfacing Rotted Wood and Charcoal." 1946 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Papers and Articles: "Race Prejudice and Negro-White Relations in the Army." 1947 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Papers and Articles: "Chicago's Neighborhoods of the Future." Working Titles: "River City: Vertical Villages of the Future" and "River City: The Need of Communities and Neighborhoods." 1947 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Papers and Articles: "Race Prejudice" with A Report on Minorities in Denver (first 31 pages only). 1948 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Papers and Articles: "Concerning Movement." 1949 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Papers and Articles: "The Freudian Error as an Aid in Determining Attitudes." 1949 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Papers and Articles: "Personality in Culture." late 1940s (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Papers and Articles: "Ceramic Traits and What They Indicate as to the Nature of Culture Contacts between the Anasazi and Mogollon." 1950 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Papers and Articles: "Military Government on Truk." Original Title: "On Governing of Native Peoples." 1950 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Papers and Articles: "The Concepts of Dissociation and Awareness as Factors in Change in the Cross Cultural Process." 1950 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Papers and Articles: "To Be One's Self." early 1950s(?) (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Papers and Articles: "Southwestern Dated Ruins. VI" 1951 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Papers and Articles: "'The Americans Will Split the Difference.'" after 1951 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Papers and Articles: The Analysis of Culture with George L. Trager. 1953 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Papers and Articles: "Human Nature at Home and Abroad " with George L. Trager. 1953 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Papers and Articles: Vulnerability, Culturally Considered." 1953 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Papers and Articles: "On the Nature of Things" or "The Nature of Things." after 1953 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Papers and Articles: "Culture and Communication: A Model and an Analysis with George L. Trager." 1954 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Papers and Articles: "The Anthropology of Manners." 1955 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Papers and Articles: "Orientation and Training in Government for Work Overseas." 1955, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Papers and Articles: "Training." 1955 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Papers and Articles: "A Microcultural Analysis of Time." 1956, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Papers and Articles: "Two Ways of Looking at Things." 1956 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Book Reviews. 1940 (Box 40, Folder 29)
    Population Changes in the Rio Grande Glazed-Paint Area, H.P. Mera, 1940.
    Anasazi Painted Pottery in Field Musuem of Natural History, Paul S. Martin and Elizabeth S. Willis, No Date.
    Mirror for Man, Clyde Kluckhohn, 1950.
    On Begin Human, Ashley Montagu, 1950.
    The Meaning of Anxiety, Rollo May, 1952.
    Man's Search for Himself, Rollo May, 1954.
    Nonverbal Communication: Notes on the Visual Perception of Human Relations, Jurgen Ruesch and Weldon Kees, 1956.
  - ETH Quotes: Comments/Discussions by or about; Interviews with ETH; References to ETH or to His Work; Citations. 1956 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Papers and Articles: "The Game." 1959 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Papers and Articles: "What Underdeveloped Countries Do Not Want." 1959 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Papers and Articles: "Introduction" to AAA Handbook. 1950s (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Papers and Articles: "Training for Cross-Cultural Work as a Selection Device." 1950s (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Papers and Articles: "When Ideas Conflict--What Can Be Done?--From the Viewpoint of a Social Anthropologist." 1950s (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Papers and Articles: ETH Quotes, etc. 1950 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - The Silent Language: Correspondence. 1955-1957 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - The Silent Language: Correspondence. 1958 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - The Silent Language: Correspondence. 1959 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - The Silent Language: Correspondence. 1960-1979 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - The Silent Language: Permissions to Quote from, Granted/Denied. 1961-1968 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - The Silent Language: Permissions to Quote from, Granted/Denied. 1969-1971 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - The Silent Language: Permissions to Quote from, Granted/Denied. 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - The Silent Language: Permissions to Quote from, Granted/Denied. 1974-1979 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - The Silent Language: Personal/Complimentary Copies. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - The Silent Language: Reviews, Notices, etc. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - The Silent Language: Use of PMS. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - The Silent Language: Excerpts, Adaptations, etc. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. Doubleday & Company, Inc., Garden City, New York. 1959 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. A Premier Book, Fawcett Publications, Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut, July 1967 (first printing). 1961 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. A Fawcett Premier Book, Fawcett Publications, Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut, (ninth printing). 1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. A Fawcett Premier Book, Fawcett Publications, Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut. No Date (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. Affiliated East-West Press Pvt. Ltd, New Dehli, India. 1973 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. Anchor Books, Anchor Press/Doubleday, Garden City, New York. 1973 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. Nan'un-do, Tokyo, Edited with Notes by Saburo Oe. No Date (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - The Silent Language: English Editions. Lin Kon Book, Sound & Gift Co./Imperial Books & Records Co., no publisher. No Date (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - The Silent Language: French Edition. ( La Langage Silencieux). Maison Mame, no publisher. 1973 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - The Silent Language: Japanese Edition, no publisher, Tokyo. No Date (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Papers, Articles: "International Communication: A Guide to Men of Action" with William Foote Whyte. Original Title, "The Invisible Sell: A Fourth Dimension in Overseas Business." 1960 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Language of Space." 1960 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Papers, Articles: "Linguistic Models in the Analysis of Culture." 1960 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Silent Language in Overseas Business." 1960 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Papers, Articles: "Architecture and Mental Health." after 1960 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Papers, Articles: "Spatial Relations and Man's Physiology and Psychology." Published as "Proxemics: The Study of Man's Spatial Relations." 1961, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Investigation of Out-of Awareness Cultural Systems with Special Reference to Times and Space. 1962 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Madding Crowd: Space and Its Organization as a Factor in Mental Health." 1962 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Papers, Articles: "Our Silent Language: 'Ocultos' Speak Louder Than Words". Usually reprinted as "The Silent Language." 1962 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Papers, Articles: Sensitivity and Empathy at Home and Abroad: Three Leatherbee Lectures, Harvard University, Graduate School of Business Administration. Includes: i "Actions Speak Louder Than Words," ii "Microspace as a System of Communication," and iii "Interpersonal Relations in an Inter-culture Setting. Is Empathy Enough?" 1962 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Papers, Articles: "Silent Assumptions in Social Communication." 1962, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Papers, Articles: "Spatial Features of Man's Biotope." 1962 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - (Folder number used to fill a misnumbered sequence.) (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Papers, Articles: "Man and Space: Each Contains the Other." 1963 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Papers, Articles: "Quality in Architecture" An Anthropological View." 1963 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Papers, Articles: "A System for the Notation of Proxemic Behavior." 1963 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Papers, Articles: "Social Distance." Circa 1963 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes, etc. 1963 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Papers, Articles: "Adumbration as a Feature of Intercultural Communication." 1964 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Papers, Articles: " The Anthropology of Space." 1964 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes, etc. 1964 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Papers, Articles: "Human Adaptability to High Density." 1965 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Role of Patterns in the Description and Analysis of Culture." 1965 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Papers, Articles: "Territorial Needs and Limits." 1965 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes, etc. 1965 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Papers, Articles: "Temporal Structural Points in Systems of Non-Verbal Communication." 1966 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes, etc. 1966 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1963-1964 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1965 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1966 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1967 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1968-1971 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Anchor Books/Doubleday/ 1967-1971 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Correspondence with Roma McNickle, editor. 1962-1965 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden Dimension: References to Be Checked. (Box 44, Folder 7a)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Permissions for Use of Quotes, Correspondence, Summaries. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Persimssions for Use of Photos, Correspondence. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Permissions to Quote From, Granted. 1967-1970 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Permissions to Quote From, Granted. 1971-1975 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Permissions to Quote From, Granted. 1976-1979 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Permissions toQuote From, Denied. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Personal/Complimentary Copies, Lists. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Publicity, Correspondence with Flyers, Ad, etc. (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Reviews. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Excerpts, Adaptations. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Manuscript, Chapters i-iii. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Manuscript, Chapters iv-vii. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Manuscript, Chapters viii-x. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Manuscript, Chapters xi-xiv. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - The Hidden Dimension: The New Dimension: "Carbon of Original Ms Sent to Doubleday" Part I, Chapters i-iii. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - The Hidden Dimension: The New Dimension: "Carbon of Original Ms Sent to Doubleday" Part II, Chapters iv-vii. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - The Hidden Dimension: The New Dimension: "Carbon of Original Ms Sent to Doubleday" Part III, Chapters viii-ix. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden Dimension: The New Dimension: "Carbon of Original Ms Sent to Doubleday" Part VI, Chapters x-xiv. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Master Carbon. Part I, Bibliography, Table of Contents, Author's Preface, Chapters i-iii. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Master Carbon. Part II, Chapters iv-ix; Part III, Chapters x-xiv, List of Illustrations. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Master Carbon. Appendices i-ii. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - The Hidden Dimension: "Final Edited Version for Printer:" Through Chapter iii. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Chapters iv-ix. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Chapters x-xii. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Chapters xiii-xiv. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Drawings, Loose and Paste-ups. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Drawings, Loose and Paste-ups. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Photos and Negatives. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden Dimension: English Editions. Doubleday & Company, Inc., Garden City, New York. 1966 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - The Hidden Dimension: English Editions. Anchor Books/Doubleday & Company, Inc., Garden City, New York. 1969 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - The Hidden Dimension: English Editions. The Bodley Head, Ltd., London. 1969 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - The Hidden Dimension: English Editions. The Fihõsha Ltd., Tokyo (chapters iv-vi, ix, appendix; edited with notes by Masami Hatano; signed presentation copy, editor to authors. 1976 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - The Hidden Dimension: English Editions. Shohakusha, Tokyo (chapters xi-xii; edtied with notes by Mitsuru Shinomiya.) 1974 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - The Hidden Dimension: French Edition. La Dimenion Cachée, Édition du Seuil, Paris. 1971 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - The Hidden Dimension: German Edition. Die Sprache Des Raumes, Pädogogisher Verlag Schwann, Düsseldorf. 1976 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Hungarian Edition. Rejtett Dimenziók, Gondolat, no publisher (introduction by Szalai Sándor). 1975 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Italian Editions. La Dimensione Nascosta, Valentino Bompiani, Milano (introduction by Umberto Eco). 1968 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Italian Editions. Valentino Bompiani, Milano (3rd edition). 1968 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Norwegian Edition. Den Skjulte Dimension, Nyt Nordisk Forlag, Arnold Busck, Kobenhavn. 1973 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Polish Editions. Ukryty Wymiar, Panstwosy Instytut Wydawniczy, Warszawa. 1976 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Polish Editions. Ukryty Wymiar, Panstwosy Instytut Wydawniczy, Warszawa. 1978 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Portuguese Edition. A Dimensão Oculta, Livraria Francisco Alves Editora, Rio de Janeiro. 1977 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Spanish Editions. La Dimensión Oculta, Siglo veintiuno editores, México D.F. 1972 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - The Hidden Dimension: Spanish Editions. Siglo veintiuno editores, México D.F. (4th edition). 1978 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Papers, Articles: "And If the Deer Die Off, What Will Happen to Use in Our Cities?" 1967? (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Papers, Articles: "Human Need and Inhuman Cities." 1967 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Papers, Articles: "Human Need and Inhuman Cities (reprints)." 1967 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Papers, Articles: "Positive and Negative Reinforcement." 1967 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Papers, Articles: "To Each His Own--The Manpower Potential in Our Ethnic Groups." 1967 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review, The Myth of the Machine, Lewis Mumford. 1967 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1967 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Papers, Articles: "Environmental Communication." 1968, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Influence of Space on Teacher-Student Relations." 1968 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Papers, Articles: "Proxemics." 1968 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Papers, Articles: "Proxemics." 1968 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Papers, Articles: "Proxemics." 1968 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Papers, Articles: "Seeing & Believing." 1968 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review, Eye and Brain: The Psychology of Seeing, R.L. Gregory. 1968 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1968 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Papers, Articles: "Development, Stratification and Prejudice in Development Programs." 1969 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Language of Personal Space" with Mildred Reed Hall. 1969 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Papers, Articles: "Listening Behavior: Some Cultural Differences." 1969 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review, Ecological Psychology: Concepts and Methods for Studying the Environment of Human Behavior, Roger G. Barker. 1969 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review: House Form and Culture, Amos Rapoport. 1969 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1969 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Papers, Articles: "Art, Space and the Human Experience." 1970 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Papers, Articles: "Forword" to Spatial Behavior of Older People. 1969 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1970 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Papers, Articles: "Communication and Design." 1971 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Paradox of Culture." 1971 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Papers, Articles: "Proxemics and Design." 1971 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Sounds of Silence" with Mildred Reed Hall. Orginaly called "The Language of Behavior." 1971 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Sounds of Silence" with Mildred Reed Hall. Orginaly called "The Language of Behavior." 1973-1976 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Papers, Articles: "The Sounds of Silence" with Mildred Reed Hall. Orginaly called "The Language of Behavior." 1976-1979 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1971 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Papers, Articles: "Architectural Implications of the Thermal Qualities of the Human Skin." 1972 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Papers, Articles: "High Rise Living: Can One Design Serve Both Young and Old?" or"...Can One Design Serve Both Swingers and Squares" with Gerda Wekerle. 1972 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1972 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Papers, Articles: "Mental Health Research and Out-of -Awareness Cultural Systems." 1973 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Papers, Articles: "ETH Quotes. 1973 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Papers, Articles: "Adumbrative Behavior in High and Low Context Situations." 1974 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Papers, Articles: "Meeting Man's Basic Spatial Needs in Artificial Environments." 1974 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review, The Old Ones of New Mexico, Robert Coles. 1974 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1974 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Papers, Articles: Book Review, Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance, Robert M. Pirsig. 1975 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Papers, Articles: ETH Quotes. 1975 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Preliminary Draft: Part II, Section 1-2. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Preliminary Draft. Part II, Section 3, Coding Sheet, Equipment Appendix, Brochures, and Note on Equipment. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Early Version: Part I: Front Matter, chapter 1; Letter with Editorial Comment form Roma McNickle. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Part I, Chapters 2-5. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Part II, p.99. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Part II, p. 100, Appendix B. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Part II, Coder's Manual (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Part III, Records/Transcription Procedures, Bibliography and References. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Edited Later Draft. Chapters 1-2. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Chapters 3-5. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume I, Chapters 1-2. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume I, Chapters 3-5. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume I, Chapter 6. (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume II, Part I, Sections 1-2. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume II, Part I, Section 3. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume II, Part II, Section 1. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume II, Part II, Section 2. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Volume II, Part II, Section 3, Appendices A-D. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Appendix E, Bibliography. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Final Typescript for Publisher, Artwork, Photos, and Negatives. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Handbook for Proxemic Research: Society for the Anthropology of Visual Communication, Washington D.C. Published Text. 1974 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: "Deere Study, Key Interviews." (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: "Deere--Interview Questionaires & Tables." (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: "Deere Summary Reports on Interviews (x3) & Visits." (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: Deere Publicity and Brochures. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: "Challenge to an Architect", Administrative Center Brochure. (Box 52, Folder 4a)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: Administrative Center Brochure. (Box 52, Folder 4b)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: "Farm Technology Plows Ahead at John Deere," Fortune, December. 1966 (Box 52, Folder 4c)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: Eric Stoller, Photos a-d. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: Preliminary Draft. 1972 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: Edited Photocopy of Preliminary Draft, Checked by Hewitt. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: The Sunstone Press, Santa Fe, New Mexico. Published Text. 1975 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - The Fourth Dimension in Architecture: The Sunstone Press, Santa Fe, New Mexico. Published Text (another copy). 1975 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Beyond Culture: Correspondence with Doubleday. 1971-1974 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Beyond Culture: Correspondence. 1975-1977 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Culture: Permissions for Use of Quotes, Correspondence, Summaries - Barker-Hughes. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Beyond Culture: Permissions for Use of Quotes, Correspondence, Summaries - Keene. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Beyond Culture: Permissions to Quote From. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Beyond Culture: Complimentary Copies. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Beyond Culture: Publicity, Correspondence, Ads, Flyers. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Beyond Culture: Reviews. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Beyond Culture: Excerpts, Adaptations. (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Beyond Culture: Original Manuscript, Preface and Introduction. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Beyond Culture: Original Manuscript, Chapter 1. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Culture: Original Manuscript, Chapter 2. (Box 54, Folder 3)